SARASWATHI ANBU

sara.karthik85@gmail.com

CAREER OBJECTIVE

Software engineer with over 5 years experience in developing and testing of web and desktop applications primarily for the banking and financial industry.

I'm actively seeking for a software engineer role enhancing my knowledge and experience gained and be an active part of the organization's progress.

EDUCATION

Jun 2009 – May 2011, Master of Business Administration (General), Alagappa University, India

Jun 2003 – May 2007, Bachelor of Engineering, Electronics & Communication Engineering, Anna University, India

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Oct 2010 – Oct 2013, Senior Systems Engineer, Infosys Limited, India Client: Bank of America

- Developed an end to end automated compliance management application to manage the corporate general ledger account usage policy for Bank of America.
- Developed a secure internal banking web application using ASP.NET, C# enabling users to add/modify/view/remove financial transaction records based on their roles.
- Lead the optimization of various backend jobs including creation of SQL procedures to validate the insertion of millions of database records as against the front end increasing the application response time by 35%.
- Lead a 3 member team including task assignment, project guidance and tracking across all phases of the project.

Aug 2008 – Oct 2010, Systems Engineer, Rifluxyss software solutions Limited, India.

- Lead the building of a digital scanning service (https://scandigital.com/) to digitize photos, tapes & reels.
- Built a desktop application for the custom digitization hardware to digitize photos, tapes & reels.
- Developed a web application to enable users to download and access digitized assets via a downloader tool making the ScanDigital site download photos from its affiliate server using third party API with authentication.
- Handled change requirements and provided support for ScanDigital's digitization website. Developed a drag and drop functionality for a gallery page using JavaScript for photo selection of the user

Aug 2007 – Aug 2008, Systems Engineer, Indian Space Research Organisation Satellite Center, India

- Effectively carried out the testing procedures for the various embedded chips for satellite systems and documented the fixes.
- Performed embedded chip design verification and making the appropriate correction using software tools.

TECHNOLOGY SUMMARY

Languages: PHP; C#; ASP.Net (MVC); AJAX; JavaScript; JQuery; Bootstrap; Angular; REST API;

Tools: Visual Studio 2017, Visual Studio Code, GIT, JIRA

Database: MS SQL, My SQL

SKILLS

[Software Development]

- Web Development
- Software Programming
- End to end design for both web and desktop software applications

[Communication]

- Business level proficiency in English (Reading & Writing).
- Beginner German (A1).

[Leadership]

- Active participant in recruitment teams primarily focused on recruiting engineers for software engineer and test engineer roles.
- Organized and conducted various team events.
- Mentorship of junior members in the team helping them to technically adapted to the system
- Organized Knowledge sharing meeting among the different teams

ACCOMPLISHMENTS

Completed Front-End JavaScript Frameworks: **Angular** certification offered by The Hong Kong University of Science and Technology. (December 2018) https://www.coursera.org/account/accomplishments/verify/R6TLFPY8DVZW

PERSONAL DETAILS

- Nationality: Indian
- Work Authorization: B-Permit holder, Eligible to work in Switzerland